<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aubm</title>
    <link>https://www.aubm.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aubm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 19:02:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aubm.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everybody should play Dungeons and Dragons</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/everybody-should-play-dungeons-and-dragons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 19:02:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/everybody-should-play-dungeons-and-dragons/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Saturday, July 3, 2021, it&amp;rsquo;s 1:55 p.m. in Montreal, 7:55 p.m. in Toulouse. I have not counted the hours over the past few months that I have spent preparing for this moment. The stress level is high, as well as the excitement. In five minutes, three people in Montreal and two more in Toulouse will join on the same Discord server. They have already created an account on Roll20, the character sheets are ready, we are just about to officially start our Dungeons and Dragons campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How my programming skills helped me to become better with my personal finances (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-my-programming-skills-helped-me-with-my-personal-finances-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 18:12:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-my-programming-skills-helped-me-with-my-personal-finances-part-1/</guid>
      <description>About two years ago I moved from France to Canada which raised some questions regarding how I would manage money. Some of them had to do with how taxes work. I also wondered what portion of my euros I should convert and transfer to my Canadian bank account. But the question I was most eager to solve was how much money it was going to cost me to maintain a train of life similar to the one I had in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:39:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>WEBSITE DISCLAIMER The information provided on this Site https://www.aubm.net is for general informational purposes only. All information on the Site is provided in good faith, however we make no representation or warranty of any kind, express or implied, regarding the accuracy, adequacy, validity, reliability, availability, or completeness of any information on the Site. UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCE SHALL WE HAVE ANY LIABILITY TO YOU FOR ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE OF ANY KIND INCURRED AS A RESULT OF THE USE OF THE SITE OR RELIANCE ON ANY INFORMATION PROVIDED ON THE SITE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le Moment le Plus Triste du Z Event 2022 🇫🇷</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/le-moment-le-plus-triste-du-z-event-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 01:41:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/le-moment-le-plus-triste-du-z-event-2022/</guid>
      <description>Cette page a été déplacée ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saddest Moment of the Z Event 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-saddest-moment-of-the-z-event-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 23:09:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-saddest-moment-of-the-z-event-2022/</guid>
      <description>It was when president Macron tweeted about it, and here is why.
First and foremost, quoting Wikipedia for those who might not have heard about it.
The Z Event is a francophone charity project created by Adrien Nougaret and Alexandre Dachary (respectively known under the pseudonyms ZeratoR and Dach) whose goal is to bring together French streamers to collect donations that will support a charity. Organized on the Twitch streaming site, it has raised more money than any other french video gaming event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Use Dependency Injection, If Not For Me, Do It For Your Unit Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/please-use-dependency-injection-if-not-for-me-do-it-for-your-unit-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 18:10:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/please-use-dependency-injection-if-not-for-me-do-it-for-your-unit-tests/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; see title.
Long time no see, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we haven&amp;rsquo;t talked about Go. I still love the language, I still use it on a daily basis, and today I feel like talking a bit about dependency injection. So hold on to your seats because it&amp;rsquo;s going to get boring very soon, or not we&amp;rsquo;ll see.
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem? Take the following file. It has a Fetch function that takes base currency and a target currency, and it fetches the exchange rate between the two currencies by contacting an API that has that information in JSON format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I like Slack as much as I like being interrupted at my desk</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/i-like-slack-as-much-as-i-like-being-interrupted-at-my-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 21:18:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/i-like-slack-as-much-as-i-like-being-interrupted-at-my-desk/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I haven’t had a long debate about which communication tools we should use and how we should use them as a team. Since the global health situation won’t let us have this debate where it normally belongs - the bar - I’ll just put some thoughts here and maybe share a few unpopular opinions.
The other day I was using Slack to chat with my project manager Johana and just about when we finished our conversation, my doorbell suddenly rang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 ways of shooting yourself in the foot when writing applications in Go</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/3-ways-of-shooting-yourself-in-the-foot-when-writing-applications-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 09:40:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/3-ways-of-shooting-yourself-in-the-foot-when-writing-applications-in-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Go for a few years now and today I want to share some experience. This post is about a few funny and somewhat not obvious bad Go patterns. This is 3 ways of shooting yourself in the foot when writing applications in Go.
Channels overflow Among many other things, Go is great for its concurrent programming model. Goroutines, channels and packages from the standard library like sync offer a great experience when it comes to solving problems with concurrency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Kubernetes API</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/extending-the-kubernetes-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 18:00:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/extending-the-kubernetes-api/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes offers various ways to add custom functionalities and to modify the way built-in features work. Today I want to talk about extending Kubernetes by using custom resources and controllers. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a close look at how to do that, but first a quick story!
Why extending Kubernetes As I mentioned in my previous post, my journey on the cloud began with Google App Engine. As a developer, I was pretty happy with the path to production of the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Certified Kubernetes Application Developer and Administrator Certifications</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-certified-kubernetes-application-developer-and-administrator-certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 15:00:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-certified-kubernetes-application-developer-and-administrator-certifications/</guid>
      <description>After a few years of daily work with Kubernetes, I decided to become a Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) as well as a Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA). As I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken and successfully passed the exams, I figured this was a good opportunity for a story.
My background experience My first steps with Kubernetes go back a few years ago, when I began experiencing on Google Cloud Platform and was amazed by how easy and fun it was to deploy applications on Google App Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case of a Git Linear History</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-case-of-a-git-linear-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-case-of-a-git-linear-history/</guid>
      <description>I recently left a team where I was the lead developer for about three years. I was regularly asked about why I wanted to keep the history of the git repository linear. Most of the time (but not always), the question came from fellow developers having a hard time rebasing a work branch.
As a matter of fact, the question was also asked multiple times on StackOverflow, especially as What are advantages of keeping linear history in git or Git workflow and rebase vs merge questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being the Best Is Not Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/being-the-best-is-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 09:40:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/being-the-best-is-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>Being the best, meaning having the best technical skills. It is not a rare thing for me to meet with someone, typically a fellow developer, who will give me the impression that having figured it all out about a technology is what makes you the best match for working on a particular project.
I believe this statement is wrong and it may sound straightforward to say. But identifying what we are missing when we think like that is a bit less obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Better Promote Your Bad Ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-to-better-promote-your-bad-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-to-better-promote-your-bad-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Ever found yourself in a situation where you had to promote an idea that you thought it was brilliant, but your co-workers did not?
We don&amp;rsquo;t always have good ideas, sometimes we poorly elaborate our instincts, and whatever we come up with doesn&amp;rsquo;t pass the test of the evaluation by our pairs. If your colleagues have presented robust and logical arguments, then it&amp;rsquo;s hard to defend your idea further.
The thing is, if you really care about these ideas, then it is really a shame that it would only take a solid and well established argumentation for them to be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
