<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Aubm</title>
    <link>https://www.aubm.net/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Aubm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 18:00:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aubm.net/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Kubernetes API</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/extending-the-kubernetes-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 18:00:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/extending-the-kubernetes-api/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes offers various ways to add custom functionalities and to modify the way built-in features work. Today I want to talk about extending Kubernetes by using custom resources and controllers. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a close look at how to do that, but first a quick story!
Why extending Kubernetes As I mentioned in my previous post, my journey on the cloud began with Google App Engine. As a developer, I was pretty happy with the path to production of the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Certified Kubernetes Application Developer and Administrator Certifications</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-certified-kubernetes-application-developer-and-administrator-certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 15:00:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-certified-kubernetes-application-developer-and-administrator-certifications/</guid>
      <description>After a few years of daily work with Kubernetes, I decided to become a Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) as well as a Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA). As I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken and successfully passed the exams, I figured this was a good opportunity for a story.
My background experience My first steps with Kubernetes go back a few years ago, when I began experiencing on Google Cloud Platform and was amazed by how easy and fun it was to deploy applications on Google App Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
