<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Aubm</title>
    <link>https://www.aubm.net/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Aubm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 01:41:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.aubm.net/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Le Moment le Plus Triste du Z Event 2022 🇫🇷</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/le-moment-le-plus-triste-du-z-event-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 01:41:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/le-moment-le-plus-triste-du-z-event-2022/</guid>
      <description>🇬🇧 Read in english here 🇬🇧
C’était quand le président Macron a tweeté à propos de l&#39;événement, voilà pourquoi.
Tout d’abord, je cite Wikipedia pour ceux qui ne connaîtraient pas le Z Event.
 Le Z Event est un projet caritatif créé par Adrien Nougaret et Alexandre Dachary - respectivement connus sous les pseudonymes ZeratoR et Dach - réunissant des streameurs francophones afin de récolter des dons qui permettront de soutenir une ou plusieurs associations caritatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saddest Moment of the Z Event 2022 🇬🇧</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-saddest-moment-of-the-z-event-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 23:09:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-saddest-moment-of-the-z-event-2022/</guid>
      <description>It was when president Macron tweeted about it, and here is why.
First and foremost, quoting Wikipedia for those who might not have heard about it.
 The Z Event is a francophone charity project created by Adrien Nougaret and Alexandre Dachary (respectively known under the pseudonyms ZeratoR and Dach) whose goal is to bring together French streamers to collect donations that will support a charity. Organized on the Twitch streaming site, it has raised more money than any other french video gaming event.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>