<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on Aubm</title>
    <link>https://www.aubm.net/tags/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on Aubm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 18:12:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aubm.net/tags/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How my programming skills helped me to become better with my personal finances (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-my-programming-skills-helped-me-with-my-personal-finances-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 18:12:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-my-programming-skills-helped-me-with-my-personal-finances-part-1/</guid>
      <description>About two years ago I moved from France to Canada which raised some questions regarding how I would manage money. Some of them had to do with how taxes work. I also wondered what portion of my euros I should convert and transfer to my Canadian bank account. But the question I was most eager to solve was how much money it was going to cost me to maintain a train of life similar to the one I had in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le Moment le Plus Triste du Z Event 2022 🇫🇷</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/le-moment-le-plus-triste-du-z-event-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 01:41:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/le-moment-le-plus-triste-du-z-event-2022/</guid>
      <description>Cette page a été déplacée ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saddest Moment of the Z Event 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-saddest-moment-of-the-z-event-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 23:09:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/the-saddest-moment-of-the-z-event-2022/</guid>
      <description>It was when president Macron tweeted about it, and here is why.
First and foremost, quoting Wikipedia for those who might not have heard about it.
The Z Event is a francophone charity project created by Adrien Nougaret and Alexandre Dachary (respectively known under the pseudonyms ZeratoR and Dach) whose goal is to bring together French streamers to collect donations that will support a charity. Organized on the Twitch streaming site, it has raised more money than any other french video gaming event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I like Slack as much as I like being interrupted at my desk</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/i-like-slack-as-much-as-i-like-being-interrupted-at-my-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 21:18:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/i-like-slack-as-much-as-i-like-being-interrupted-at-my-desk/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I haven’t had a long debate about which communication tools we should use and how we should use them as a team. Since the global health situation won’t let us have this debate where it normally belongs - the bar - I’ll just put some thoughts here and maybe share a few unpopular opinions.
The other day I was using Slack to chat with my project manager Johana and just about when we finished our conversation, my doorbell suddenly rang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being the Best Is Not Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/being-the-best-is-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 09:40:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/being-the-best-is-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>Being the best, meaning having the best technical skills. It is not a rare thing for me to meet with someone, typically a fellow developer, who will give me the impression that having figured it all out about a technology is what makes you the best match for working on a particular project.
I believe this statement is wrong and it may sound straightforward to say. But identifying what we are missing when we think like that is a bit less obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Better Promote Your Bad Ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-to-better-promote-your-bad-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aubm.net/posts/how-to-better-promote-your-bad-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Ever found yourself in a situation where you had to promote an idea that you thought it was brilliant, but your co-workers did not?
We don&amp;rsquo;t always have good ideas, sometimes we poorly elaborate our instincts, and whatever we come up with doesn&amp;rsquo;t pass the test of the evaluation by our pairs. If your colleagues have presented robust and logical arguments, then it&amp;rsquo;s hard to defend your idea further.
The thing is, if you really care about these ideas, then it is really a shame that it would only take a solid and well established argumentation for them to be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
